Guide to the David A. Kessler Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1953-2000, Series I
  - Safer Cigarette [legal risks to talk about], 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 371)
  - Saiger, George, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Saunders, James A., 1994 (Box 8, Folder 373)
  - Scenes
    - General, undated (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - Light, Long, Lorraine, Natanblut, Zeller, undated (Box 8, Folder 375 - 379)
  - Schori, Tom, 1995, undated (Box 8, Folder 380)
  - Schuller, Robert H., 1992 (Box 8, Folder 381)
  - Schweitzer, Stuart O., 1999 (Box 8, Folder 382)
  - Secret tobacco document quotes, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 383)
  - Secretary's briefing on tobacco, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Seltzer, Carl, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Shalala, Donna, undated (Box 8, Folder 386)
  - Shapiro, Renie
    - Notes, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 387)
    - Tobacco papers [period beyond hearing], 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - Sheet material, 1978-1987 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Shinn on history of Council for Tobacco Research [friends], 1978 (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Siemann, Dirk H., 1995 (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Slade, John, 1989-1998, undated (Box 8, Folder 392 - 400)
  - Smoked fish, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 401)
  - Smokeless, 1973-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 402 - 406)
  - Smokeless cigarette [ R.J. Reynolds memo], 1987 September 17 (Box 8, Folder 406A)
  - Smokeless tobacco [Ilisa Bernstein files], 1972-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 407 - 413)
  - Solvents
    - Articles and correspondence, 1979-1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 414)
    - OSHA, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 415)
  - Soucek, Mike, 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 416 - 419)
  - Special projects, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 420)
  - Spiller [suggestions as to other agency information], 1994 (Box 9, Folder 421)
  - Stark-Vancs, Virginia ["The Last Patient"], undated (Box 9, Folder 422)
  - Studies on cigarettes, papers and nicotine, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 423)
  - Sudafed, undated (Box 9, Folder 424)
  - Sullivan, Louis W.
    - General, 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 425)
    - Briefing book, undated (Box 9, Folder 426)
  - Surgeon general
    - Attacking, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 427)
    - Report, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 428)
  - Synar, Michael L.
    - General, 1992-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 429)
    - Before Health and Environment Subcommittee, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 430)
    - Funeral and medical records, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 431)
  - Talk of the Nation notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 432)
  - Tar wars [educational material], undated (Box 9, Folder 433)
  - Taylor, Mike [food labeling], undated (Box 9, Folder 434)
  - Ternouth looking for Y1, undated (Box 9, Folder 435)
  - Terry, Luther, 1962-1972 (Box 9, Folder 436)
  - Testimony drafts, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 437 - 439)
  - Theophylline, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 440)
  - Thermogravametric, undated (Box 9, Folder 441)
  - Third parties and appropriations testimony, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 442)
  - Third World strategy, undated (Box 9, Folder 443)
  - Thirty years of industry position, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 444)
  - Thompson, Penny, undated (Box 9, Folder 445)
  - Threats and hate mail, 1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 446)
  - Tisch, undated (Box 9, Folder 447)
  - Tobacco [grades, processing, production], 1993-1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 448)
  - Tobacco company strategies to undermine tobacco control activities at WHO, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 449)
  - Tobacco free kids, undated (Box 9, Folder 450)
  - Tobacco implementation plan [FDA notebook], undated (Box 9, Folder 451)
  - Tobacco industry positions on smoking and health, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 452)
  - Tobacco media campaign [material from Sharon Natanblut], 1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 453 - 455)
  - Tobacco seeds and RJR, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 456)
  - Tobacco settlement, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 457)
  - Tobacco working group, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 458 - 464)
  - Torbeck v. Zoon, 1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 465)
  - Transcript relative to surrogate endpoints [meeting of advisory committee], 1991 (Box 10, Folder 466)
  - Trans-disciplinary Tobacco Research Center, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 467)
  - Translation of Brazilian patent, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 468)
  - Tylenol tampering, 1983-2000, undated (Box 10, Folder 469 - 470)
  - Up from the bomb shelter: alternative courses for the tobacco industry [report], 1978 (Box 10, Folder 471)
  - Valdya, Sharead G. [National Organization for Tobacco Eradication], 2000 (Box 10, Folder 472)
  - Videx [didanosine, ddI], 1991-1992, undated (Box 10, Folder 473)
  - Walsh, John on New York Times and recombinant bovine somatotropin, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 474)
  - Wernsman, Earl [manipulation of genes in tobacco], 1994 (Box 10, Folder 475)
  - White House correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 10, Folder 476)
  - Williams, Merrill, 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 477 - 478)
  - Winston Lights, undated (Box 10, Folder 479)
  - Witt, Ann, 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 480)
  - Women and smoking, 1973-1995, undated (Box 10, Folder 481 - 482)
  - World Health Organization [tobacco industry attempts to undermine tobacco control at WHO], 2000 (Box 10, Folder 483 - 484)
  - Wykoff, Randy, undated (Box 10, Folder 485)
  - Y1, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 486)
  - Yersinia contamination of red blood cells, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 487)
  - Young, Frank
    - Columbia Law School [remarks], 1988 (Box 10, Folder 488)
    - Helms, Jesse, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 489)
    - Premier, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 490)
    - Teaching Columbia class, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 491)
  - Youth access to tobacco [Robert Wood Johnson Foundation], 1995 (Box 10, Folder 492)
  - Zeller, Mitch
    - Trade secret information [notes], 1994 (Box 10, Folder 493)
    - Merrill Williams documents [notes], undated (Box 10, Folder 494)
  - Zimbabwe, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 495)
- Speeches, 1990-2000, Series II
  The series consists of speeches made by Kessler while commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration and dean of the Yale University School of Medicine. The speeches were removed from fourteen notebooks and are arranged chronologically; an index to them can be found in the first folder of box eleven. Sixteen folders of "Miscellaneous remarks," which are not included in the notebooks or the index, are listed alphabetically at the end of the series.
  - Indices to notebooks, 1990-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks 1-4, 1990-1994 (Box 11, Folder 2 - 24)
  - Notebooks 5-8, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 25 - 45)
  - Notebooks 9-11, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 46 - 61)
  - Notebooks 12-14, 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 62 - 70)
  - Miscellaneous remarks
    - General, undated (Box 14, Folder 71 - 75)
    - Committee on Labor and Human Resources, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 76)
    - DdI press conference, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 77)
    - Drug Information Association, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 78)
    - First speech to policy board, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 79)
    - Food and Drug Association anti-viral drug product advisory committee, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 80)
    - Food and Drug Law Institute, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 81)
    - Going away talk at Einstein, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 82)
    - National Academy of Sciences/Institute of Medicine, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 83)
    - Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 84)
    - Subcommittee on Rural Development, Agriculture, and related agencies, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 85)
    - Tobacco talks, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 86)
    - When only the truth will do: FDA and orange juice, breast implants, and video releases, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 87)
- Chronological Files, 1977-1997, Series III
  The Chronological Files relate to the efforts of the Food and Drug Administration to regulate tobacco as a controlled substance. Culled and copied from other FDA files, the series includes clippings, memoranda, reports, and other documents that provide a narrative of the struggle of the FDA and other groups seeking to assign culpability to the tobacco industry for the health hazards of cigarettes and other products. There is considerable topical overlap and duplication with materials in Series I and IV.
  - 1977-1994 Feb (Box 15, Folder 1 - 38)
  - 1994 Mar-Jun (Box 16, Folder 39 - 61)
  - 1994 Jul-1997 May (Box 17, Folder 62 - 94)
- Food and Drug Administration Commissioner's Files, 1952-1997, Series IV
  Arranged alphabetically, the series consists of files Kessler copied and took with him after resigning from the FDA in 1997. Along with materials about tobacco, the series includes documentation of drug approval, the Competitiveness Council, Robitussin, and Similac. Folder titles and headings created by Kessler and his staff have been preserved. There may be considerable topical overlap and duplication with materials in Series I and Series III.
  - Advocacy Institute [strategy], 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Allman v. Philip Morris [Southern District of California], 1963, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Benowitz data, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Books on olfaction, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Canadian
    - Advertising, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Project Viking, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 6 - 7)
    - RJR McDonald Imperial Tobacco [youth], 1987 (Box 18, Folder 8 - 9)
    - Tobacco [Abood, Leo], 1994 (Box 18, Folder 10 - 11)
  - Catalogue of deception, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Cigarette advertising and promotion, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Cippolone documents from Edell [affidavit in Rodgers case], 1952-1994 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Competitiveness Council
    - Agnew, Ann and Michael Astrue [draft decision memorandum], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Briefing books I and II [House Committee on Human Resources], 1992 (Box 18, Folder 16 - 25)
    - Buyer's Club, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 26 - 28)
    - Calhoun, Michael, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Findings and recommendations [drug approval process], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Food and Drug Administration
      - Efficacy standard [Richard Schmalensee], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Newsclips, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Response to President's regulatory reform, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Ford Chemical News, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Gerry, Martin and Robin Carle [reply to letter from Senators Glenn, Levin and Kohl], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Hamric and Eck [documents requested by Chairman Weiss], 1992 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Holcombe, Weiss [evaluation of new drugs], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Hubbard, Allan and Ted Weiss [deliberative documents], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Kennedy, Dingell, Waxman, Kessler [safety and efficacy of drugs], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Medical Tribune [drug approvals], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 41 - 43)
    - New Yorker ["Talk of Town"], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Orlando Sentinel [cartoon on FDA labeling], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - President's press conference, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Proposed agenda topics for council study, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Quayle, Dan
      - Drug approvals [news release], 1992 (Box 18, Folder 48)
      - Remarks at FDA Drug Law Institute conference], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Report on drug approval [Kessler, Secretary], 1992 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Salmonella enteritis, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Scheineson, Marc J., 1992 (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Subpoena of documents, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Washington Post articles, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 54 - 56)
    - Waxman, Henry and David Kessler [request for FDA documents], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Weiss, Kessler [Eli Lilly & Co.], 1991 (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Wolfe, Sidney, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Working group, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 60 - 68)
  - Complaint [Sarasota case], 1994 (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Connelly, Gregory N., undated (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Council for Tobacco Research
    - Cippolone from Edell, 1958-1994 (Box 19, Folder 71 - 77)
    - Document requests, undated (Box 19, Folder 78)
    - Special projects, 1979-1994 (Box 19, Folder 79 - 80)
  - Drug Abuse Advisory Committee [meetings], 1994 (Box 19, Folder 81 - 87)
  - Eastman filter, undated (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Enfamil, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 89 - 92)
  - Fate of nicotine on the body, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 93)
  - Favor smoke-free cigarette, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 94 - 96)
  - Feiffer, undated (Box 20, Folder 97)
  - Giovino, Gary
    - Data on kids getting addicted, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 98)
    - Drug Abuse Advisory Committee, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 99)
  - Henningfield, Jack E., 1994 (Box 20, Folder 100)
  - Hill, John [on Council for Tobacco Research], 1953-1960 (Box 20, Folder 101 - 104)
  - Homburger, Freddy, 1977-1983 (Box 20, Folder 105)
  - Industry comments on addictiveness of cigarettes, undated (Box 20, Folder 106)
  - Lab data, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 107)
  - Minnesota attorney general, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 108)
  - Montreal symposium on nicotine, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 109)
  - Nicotine
    - Addiction, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 110)
    - Testing laboratories, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 111)
  - Premiere, 1987-1997 (Box 20, Folder 112 - 115)
  - Project day on quitting [Canadian], 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 116 - 118)
  - R. J. Reynolds
    - General, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 119)
    - M Vantage advertising research, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 120 - 123)
    - MacDonald operating plan, 1985-1987 (Box 21, Folder 124 - 128)
    - Press release, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 129)
    - Promotion recommendations by Trone Advertising, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 130)
  - Robitussin, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 131 - 133)
  - Roper industry advertising survey, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 134)
  - Schwan's, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 135)
  - Similac
    - Powder, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 136 - 137)
    - RTF with iron, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 138 - 142)
  - Smokeless ingredients list, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 143)
  - Sri Lankan tea threat, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 144)
  - Subcommittee on Health and the Environment, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 145)
  - Thayer Liggett & Meyers [lawyer delaying tactics], 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 146)
  - Tobacco
    - Control in Canada, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 147)
    - Industry comments, undated (Box 22, Folder 148)
  - Tobacco Industry Research Council [scientific smokescreen], 1990 (Box 22, Folder 149 - 150)
  - Toluene [John Slade], 1994 (Box 22, Folder 151)
  - U.S. tobacco
    - Documents, 1972-1985 (Box 22, Folder 152)
    - Smokeless, 1972-1994 (Box 22, Folder 153 - 156)
  - Why warnings don't work, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 157)
  - Y-1 patents, undated (Box 22, Folder 158)
- Scrapbooks, 1990-1991, Series V
  Scrapbooks contain clippings, ephemera, letters of congratulation, and other documents relating to Kessler's appointment and confirmation to the Food and Drug Administration and his first months on the job.
  - Scrapbooks 1-3, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 1 - 14)
- Briefing Books, 1950-1997, Series VI
  The series consists of the books compiled by and for Kessler for hearings on a number of Food and Drug Administration topics before committees of both houses of Congress and other government groups. The books are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Breast implants
    - General, 1971-1987 (Box 24, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Literature review and history, 1991-1995 (Box 24, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Volumes I-III, 1950-1992 (Box 24, Folder 7 - 26)
    - Volume IV, 1967-1992 (Box 25, Folder 27 - 37)
  - Childhood vaccine development hearing, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 38 - 41)
  - Congressional Appropriations hearings, 1994-1996 (Box 25, Folder 42 - 54)
  - Court of Appeals hearing [Fresh], 1991 (Box 26, Folder 55 - 58)
  - Efficacy standards, 1989-1991 (Box 26, Folder 59 - 60)
  - Folic acid subcommittee of Food Advisory Committee, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 61 - 64)
  - FDA reform, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 65)
  - Generic cases, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 66)
  - House briefing book, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 67 - 69)
  - Justification of appropriation estimates for Committee on Appropriations, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 70)
  - Red Cross, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 71 - 77)
  - Senate briefing book, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 78 - 80)
  - Tobacco hearing, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 81 - 84)
- Videotapes, 1990-1997, Series VII
  Following the organizational scheme of Kessler's office, the video tapes are arranged in two sections: Numbered and Unnumbered. Each section follows a loose chronological order. All of the tapes feature Kessler's appearances on news programs and talk shows or at conferences and hearings. The numbered videos were selected out of a greater whole of recordings that featured tobacco related news coverage not specific to Kessler's involvement, which explains the gap between numbers.
  Original video tapes may not be played; researchers must have use copies made.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Numbered
    - 4. Speech at the Thirty-Fourth conference Food and Drug Law Institute, 1990 December 12 (Box 27)
    - 5. David Kessler profiled and interviewed, 1991 September 27 (Box 27)
    - 26. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman, 1994 March 25 (Box 27)
    - 29. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce on cigarettes as "nicotine delivery systems", 1994 March 25 (Box 27)
    - 30. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce on ban of smoking in public places [NBC Nightly News], 1994 March 25 (Box 27)
    - 30a. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce on ban of smoking in public places [CNN], 1994 March 25 (Box 27)
    - 31. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce on tobacco classified as a drug and proposed ban and Congressman Waxman on proposed ban, 1994 March 25, 28 (Box 27)
    - 32a. David Kessler and Congressman Waxman; manipulation of nicotine [rat study], 1994 March 31 (Box 27)
    - 37. David Kessler testifying before Congress on Congressman Synar's legislation and nicotine as an addictive drug, 1994 April 1 (Box 27)
    - 56. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on nicotine and cigarette tampering; former Philip Morris employee V. DeNoble [2 copies], 1994 April 28 (Box 27)
    - 57. House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on nicotine and cigarette tampering, 1994 April 28 (Box 27)
    - 58. House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on nicotine; former Philip Morris employee Victor DeNoble, 1994 April 28 (Box 27)
    - 64. Dr. Kessler live - various topics including tobacco, 1994 May 24 (Box 27)
    - 68. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on tobacco [For the Record], 1994 June 21 (Box 27)
    - 70. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on tobacco [CBS], 1994 June 21 (Box 28)
    - 71. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on tobacco [CNN, 2 copies], 1994 June 21 (Box 28)
    - 72. Kessler testifies on tobacco Y-1 and Brown & Williamson, 1994 June 21 (Box 28)
    - 73. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on tobacco [2 copies], 1994 June 21 (Box 28)
    - 75. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Waxman - genetically altered nicotine, 1994 June 21 (Box 28)
    - 76. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Waxman Y-1 tobacco [NBC], 1994 June 22 (Box 28)
    - 77. Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Waxman Y-1 tobacco [CBS], 1994 June 22 (Box 28)
    - 84. Dr. Kessler with a live teen audience, 1994 July 7 (Box 28)
    - 88. Dr. Kessler and nicotine, 1994 July 13 (Box 28)
    - 91. Dr. Kessler: tobacco and FDA's regulatory policy, 1994 July 13 (Box 28)
    - 110. Speech at Columbia University School of Law; tobacco and children, 1995 March 8 (Box 28)
    - 126. Speech at Georgetown University School of Medicine on nicotine, 1995 August 16 (Box 28)
    - 129. Dr. Kessler profile, FDA under Kessler and FDA as an enforcement agency, 1995 August 27 (Box 28)
    - 130 and 131. Dr. Kessler live with call ins [two copies], 1995 August 27, 29 (Box 29)
    - 135. Speech at University of Pittsburgh, 1995 October 19 (Box 29)
    - 136. Dr. Kessler and teen smoking, 1995 October 20 (Box 29)
    - 137a. Speech on smoking and advertising at St. Jude's Children's Research Hospital, 1995 October 20 (Box 29)
    - 143. Dr. Kessler and tobacco, 1995 December (Box 29)
    - 145. Dr. Kessler profile, 1995 December 4 (Box 29)
    - 230. Dr. Kessler interviewed on tobacco final rule [Jim Lehrer and NBC], 1996 August 23, 26 (Box 29)
    - 231. Dr. Kessler interviewed on tobacco final rule [NBC], 1996 August 23 (Box 29)
  - Unnumbered (Box 29)
    - Food and Drug Law Institute thirty-fourth conference [3 tapes], 1990 December 11 (Box 30)
    - Swearing-in ceremony of Commissioner David Kessler, 1991 February 25 (Box 30)
    - "DAK", 1991 March (Box 30)
    - FDA enforcement - powers of the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act [Kessler before Waxman], 1991 July 17 (Box 30)
    - Food and Drug Administration commercial, 1991 August 8 (Box 30)
    - House Oversight [Dingell, et al.], 1991 September 12 (Box 30)
    - Breast implants and tooth whiteners, 1991 September 25, 26 (Box 30)
    - DdI, 1991 October 10 (Box 30)
    - Orange juice, silicone and Elliot Knessler, 1991 October 24 (Box 30)
    - "DAK et al." and Food and Drug Law Institute, 1991 December 10 (Box 30)
    - Silicone breast implants, 1992 January 6 (Box 30)
    - Silicone breast implants [2 tapes], 1992 January 6-February 20 (Box 31)
    - Breast implants, various topics, call-ins [2 tapes], 1992 May 14 (Box 31)
    - Pinnacle overview of FDA and Dr. Kessler's role as commissioner [4 tapes], 1992 July 11 (Box 31)
    - The open mind, 1992 November (Box 31)
    - Pepsi tampering [2 tapes], 1993 June 15-17 (Box 31)
    - Testimony before House Committee on Energy and Commerce with Congressman Waxman on tobacco, 1994 June 21 (Box 31)
    - Dr. Kessler on tobacco, 1994 June 22 (Box 31)
    - 60 Minutes profile of David Kessler, 1994 December 4 (Box 31)
    - "DAK Congress", 1995 May 1 (Box 32)
    - David Kessler on Brinkley [tobacco], 1995 August 13 (Box 32)
    - Breast implants law suits, 1995 October 22 (Box 32)
    - Michael Jackson show, 1996 October 22 (Box 32)
    - Dr. Kessler's resignation, 1996 November 25-26 (Box 32)
    - How he won the war, 1996 December 8 (Box 32)
    - Dr. Kessler on NewsHour; Dr. Kessler on Today; Liggett settlement, 1997 February 10, 26, March 20 (Box 32)
    - Dr. Kessler on MSNBC, 1997 March 25 (Box 32)
    - "DAK" [3 tapes], 1997 (Box 32)
    - "DAK" [3 tapes], undated (Box 32)
    - 60 Minutes, undated (Box 32)
- Interviews, 1994-2000, Series VIII
  The series consists of transcripts (both hard copy and floppy disk) and audio cassette recordings of interviews Kessler conducted in the course of the FDA initiative to have tobacco regulated as a drug and during research for his book A Question of Intent. The interviews are separated into two sections: Author interviews and Miscellaneous interviews. Each section includes three sub-sections: Transcripts, 3 1/4 inch floppy disks, and Audio cassette recordings, each of which is arranged alphabetically by interviewee. For a complete list of interviews, consult the Author Interviews Appendix and the Miscellaneous Interviews Appendix, which are available in the print finding aid in the repository.
  Kessler also had many of the interviews indexed. The indexes, along with miniaturized copies of the transcripts, can be found in boxes 44-45.